<eml:eml xmlns:eml="https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0"
         xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0 https://rs.gbif.org/schema/eml-gbif-profile/1.3/eml.xsd"
         packageId="https://dwcdp-ipt.gbif-test.org/resource?id=pelt_yeast_fungi/v1.0" system="http://gbif.org" scope="system"
         xml:lang="eng">
    <dataset>
        <title xml:lang="eng">Integrated Dataset of Fungi Associated with Peltigera Cyanolichens from Southern Chile</title>
        <pubDate>
        </pubDate>
        <language>eng</language>
        <abstract>
            This integrated dataset compiles fungal diversity data associated with Peltigera cyanolichens collected across southern Chile by the Microbial Ecology Lab at Universidad de Chile. It merges three occurrence resources: (1) a collection of over 1,000 Peltigera lichen thalli sampled from diverse environments, with molecular identification of the main symbionts; (2) 180 basidiomycete yeasts; and (3) 45 ascomycete fungi, both isolated from a subset of the previously collected Peltigera thalli. The isolates were identified by sequencing the ITS marker and through subsequent phylogenetic analyses.

The purpose of creating this integrated resource was to test and explore the structure and flexibility of the new Darwin Core data format, using a case study that links macro- and micro-organismal diversity within lichen symbioses.

Note:
- All data included here are publicly available and were originally published as three separate datasets: https://doi.org/10.15468/ef76hj, https://doi.org/10.15468/ceh6sr, and https://doi.org/10.15468/hw7k9r.

- Please note that some data inconsistencies or errors may be present and could be addressed in future updates.

- The use and integration of these datasets have been authorized by Yosbany Pérez and Julieta Orlando.
        </abstract>
        <intellectualRights>
            <para>This work is licensed under a <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/legalcode"><citetitle>Creative Commons Attribution (CC-BY 4.0) License</citetitle></ulink>.</para>
        </intellectualRights>
        <licensed>
            <licenseName>Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International</licenseName>
            <url>https://spdx.org/licenses/CC-BY-4.0.html</url>
            <identifier>CC-BY-4.0</identifier>
        </licensed>
        <maintenance>
            <description>
                <para></para>
            </description>
            <maintenanceUpdateFrequency>unknown</maintenanceUpdateFrequency>
        </maintenance>
    </dataset>
    <additionalMetadata>
        <metadata>
            <gbif>
                <hierarchyLevel>dataset</hierarchyLevel>
            </gbif>
        </metadata>
    </additionalMetadata>
</eml:eml>
